Hi everyone.
皆様はじめまして。
If you saw the last record, welcome back. I'm Yue.
前回の記録を見てくれた皆様はお久しぶりです。ユエです。
Maki here.
マキです。
Going to Aso for the first time since I started riding 2 months ago.
乗り初めて2か月、今日は阿蘇に行きます。
Aso? Didn't it erupt lately?
阿蘇？最近噴火しなかった？
Today's risk level is 2, we can go to the square.
今はリスクレベル2だから広場まで行ける。
Let’s go!
レッツラゴー。
Road 45, one of my favorite roads.
阿蘇公園菊池線、ここ好きなんだよね〜。
Nice road indeed but do not go too fast.
たしかにいい道だが、オーバースピードに気をつけてね。
Yea, yea.
ハイハイ〜。
Went here the day I got the bike. You can definitely feel the seasons here.
納車日にここ通ったけど、結構季節を感じる場所だな〜。
Start of October... early fall, now is late fall. I'm sure there was more leaves the first time.
10月頭... 初秋、もうすぐ終わる。 初めて通った時は葉っぱがもっとあったんだろうな〜。
True, but the road is always clean.
まあね、でも道路はいつもきれい。
Looks like a pretty place. Is it famous?
綺麗な場所だね、有名？
Kikuchi gorge. There always is people visiting here.
菊池渓谷だね、確かにここはいつも人が多いね。
Ya, it's a bit too clean and unnatural to me...
そうね、でもちょっと綺麗すぎて不自然な感じがする。
Indeed, but want to go inside one day.
確かに、でも1回は入りたいな。
Looks fun to visit indeed.
あ〜、楽しそうね〜。
By the way, how's your leg? You were injured the last time we met.
そう言えば、この前会ったとき、足をけがしていたがもう大丈夫？
It's healing. Not fully but it doesn't hurt anymore.
治りかけてる。完全ではないが、痛くなくなった。
Happy to hear that. Was a bit worried since you were paying attention to your leg when I went to search you.
そうか、よかった。何か迎えに行ったときに 足を気にしてたっぽかったから心配だった。。。
Was paying attention so you don't worry…
心配しないように気をつけてたのに。
Be careful. If you get injured again, it will take a long time to heal.
気をつけてね。今またけがしたら今度はいつ治るか。。。
Thanks... I'll be careful.
ありがとう。気をつけるよ。
Good thing I asked for a way to reach you after you dropped me at the convenience store.
コンビニに下ろしてくれた時に連絡先を聞いて良かった。
You surprised me there.
その時は結構ビックリしたな。。。
Tried to thank you but you wouldn't listen...
お礼しようとしたが聞く耳持たないから。。。
Had to keep a way to reach you...
せめて連絡先でも。
Ain't done anything tho...
大した事やってないけどな。。。
Invited you to eat as well...
食事にも誘ったし。
Sadly I don't want a uni student to treat me.
あいにく、学生におごられるのもゴメンだね。
So why did you keep chatting in English to me?
なぜ英語で返事くれるの？
Hum?
ん？
You could ignore me and act as if we didn't meet?
なかったことにして、無視すれば良かったでしょ。
Oh, that's easy.
あ〜、それは。
Not replying is pretty rude after all.
返事しないのは失礼でしょ？
You too kind.
。。。優しすぎる。
Pardon?
なんて？
I said, you better think of why you still accept me around.
なぜ私を乗せてくれるかを考えろって言ったの。
It's kidnapping! One-one-two, call the police!
誘拐だ〜110番、警察を呼べ〜。
Nonono, you're the one that asked me to show you around.
いやいやいや、おかしいよね！ 君からここら辺を案内してくれって。。。
Ahhh, someone! Help meeee!
あー、誰かー、助けてー！
Wait, I've the history of the messages for the past week.
いやいや、先週送った時からメッセージの履歴あるから！
Yesterday you said something like. “I'd like to go to nearby Aso, do you have any recommendation? Can you show me around?”
昨日に関しては「阿蘇方面を見たいです。おすすめありますか？
Or something along those lines.
って言ってたじゃん。。。一語一句ではないかもだが。。。
Uhhh, that's scary... how's your mind working?
え〜、怖い。。。きみの脳はどうなってるの？
That's not scary...
怖くないよ。。。
Nah, that's actually scary... Odd actually...
いや、ガチで怖い。
Odd is fine, it what makes me as an individual.
変で結構、それが個性であれば〜。
Individuality... actually... that doesn't make you less weird...
個性。。。いや。。。変だよね。。。
... Individuality...
。。。個性。。。
Said something weirdo?
何か言った？
You have a very specific trait.
マキさんも結構個性的な部分あったよね。
... Are you actually a weirdo?
。。。変態かな？
I found a way for you to thank me. Nothing complicated.
お礼の方法思うついた、何簡単だよ。
As long as you are in the region, call me when you want to visit a remote place.
ここら辺いる限り、遠く行きたい時俺を呼べ。
In exchange, speak English to me.
代わりに英語でしゃべって。
... Wha?
。。。えっ？
Want to practice my listening. Once we get used you speak in Japanese while I speak English.
英語のリスニングを練習して、慣れたら マキさんは日本語で、俺は英語で会話しよう。
… That's it?
。。。それだけ？
That's it.
それだけ。
It's not enough... you're at a loss...
足りないでしょ。。。損してるよ。。。
It's equivalent. If you and I are good with the trade then it's equivalent.
等価だよ。俺がオッケーで、 マキさんもオッケーなら、それは等価だよ。
… thanks.
。。。ありがとう。
Checked that we can go to the plaza at roadside station Aso.
道の駅阿蘇で確認したし、広場まで行くか〜。
It's pretty cold up there so make sure to layer up.
冷えるからちゃんと厚着してね。
I'll put this raincoat like no one ever had.
秘技、レインコートの着用！
Your side bags are in the way, so I made myself small…
サイドバッグが邪魔だからちっちゃくなったは。
Uh, how?
えっ、どうやって？
It's a secret!
ひーみーつーーー。
Yaya, smug all you want.
腹立つような立たないような。。。
What do they keep here?
ここには何があるの？
Maybe cows or horses?
ここは牛か馬かな？
Since it's November, I think they went down.
でもさすがにもう11月だから下に行っているんじゃない？
It's lovely.
ステキだね。
Cow… Like Akaushi?
牛？。。。もしかして赤牛？
Most likely yeah.
多分そうじゃないかな？
Dunno?
知らんけど？
Dunno.
知らんけど。
We're a bit short on time this time,
今回は厳しいが、いつか食べような。
Akagyudon (red beef bowl), barbecue... Have to lookup.
あか牛丼、焼き肉。。。調べないと。
If possible nothing too extreme. I'm a student remember?
まだ学生だからな。。。できればあんまりたかい物は。。。
It’s ok. I know where to go (the internet).
大丈夫、大丈夫。いい所知ってる（インターネットが）。
It's getting chilly. You ok?
結構冷えてきたね。マキさん大丈夫？
It's warm in here.
ここは暖かいよ。
That's good to hear.
それは良かった。
A mesh jacket with a few layers in fine for now but gotta lookup for some winter jacket and gloves soon.
今はメッシュジャケットとインナーで何とかなるが、 そろそろ冬用ジャケットとグローブ探さないと。。。
As a student I'm broke so nothing expensive ok?
金なしの学生だからな、高い物はちょっと。。。
I see that's common for all countries.
そこは世界共通なのか〜。
It's ok, I'll lookup for a warm windproof pouch.
大丈夫、暖かい耐風ポーチ探しておくよ〜。
Thank you. I'm not against used gear.
ありがとう。中古でも問題ない。
Finally arrived and it's cold!
着いた〜って寒っ！
Was expecting worse but the wind sure is cold...
思ったよりマシだか、風が冷たいね。
When you feel cold there is only one thing to do!
こんな寒い時はこれしかない！
Eat an ice-cream.
アイスクリーム〜。
... Are you actually an idiot?
。。。本当はアホーかな。。。
Cannot miss this. And don't you say you get warm after eating?
主食。食べたらあったまるって言うでしょ。
Never heard anything like that... Not sure if it works for cold food...
聞いたことないな。冷たい食べ物でも効くのかな？
Well, time to go back.
よし、帰るよ〜。
Okie dokie, anytime.
はいはい、いつでもー。
Don't you get tiered in that mini form?
このミニバージョン大丈夫？疲れない？
Nope. Actually it's easier, but I cannot do anything like this.
いや、こっちの方が楽だが何も出来ない。
Good to hear. Enjoy the scenery.
それはよかった。ゆっくり風景を見れるな。
Isn’t there a small scratch and shock proof pouch that could act as an airbag?
なんか小型ポーチで耐摩耗性や耐衝撃性、 エアバッグになる物はあるかな？
Oh? Maybe…
おっ、このタイミングは。。。
What is?
どうした？
Wait and see.
うふふ、ま〜見てなって。
Sunset!
日没〜。
It sure looks like it.
確かにそう見えるな。
I thought she’d a bit more surprised.
もうちょっと驚くと思ったな～。
But we must catch the sun back, or it's going to be dark and cold.
でも太陽を追いかけないと、 でないと暗くなって、冷えてくるし。
Just a bit, almost there.
はいはい、もうすぐだから～。
Sunrise!
夜明け〜。
Yaya, very funny.
ハイハイ、ワロスワロス。
Why do you know this expression?
だからなんで知ってるの！？
Hehe, Who knows?
さー、なぜでしょう？
But it sure is nice to go down like this.
こういう下りは楽しいね。
The sun is in the eyes, but the view is really pretty.
太陽が目に入るが、景色が綺麗。
No wonder we call this time golden hour.
黄金時間(マジックアワー)の名にもなっとくする。
Taking nice pictures is easier around this time.
写真映えもこの時間帯だと楽だし。
Indeed but it can be tricky in some situations.
確かに、でも場合によって難易度が高くなるんだよな。
For example?
例えば？
Since the is less light, and red tone color are stronger.
光が弱いし、赤色が目立つ。
And the low sun may be in the way for some angles.
低い太陽もアングルによっては邪魔になるし。
Playing with the light sure is complicated...
光で遊ぶのは厄介よね。
You know a lot.
わりと詳しいね。
Not really, just been around someone loving his photography.
そうでもないよ。ただ写真が大好きな人とよくいたからな。
Is that so... I have another one you can use anytime.
そうか。。。カメラあるから、使いたい時に使っていいよ。
Thanks but not right now.
ありがとう、でも今は大丈夫よ。
Wait, is this, making a small detour.
おっ、ここは、ちょっと寄り道するよ〜。
'kay!
あい！
Oh wow, this place is very pretty.
わー、綺麗な場所だな。
Want to try?
やってみる？
Nah I'm good, but maybe you want to be in the picture?
大丈夫よ、もしかして映りたい？
I can take you if you want.
撮ってあげてもいいよ。
Ahhh, I prefer to be taken only when needed.
あ〜、必要と感じた時だけ写られたいかな。。。
Now isn't the time?
今はそうではない？
Not now. How about you? Want to be in?
今はね。マキさんは？写りたい？
I'm pretty much the same.
似たようなもんよ。
I don't think framing a moment of someone is necessary most of the time.
誰かの時間を切り抜くのはだいたい不要に思えるんだよね。
That's why I mostly take videos when I'm with someone.
だからか、人とは動画を撮る方が多いかな。
I feel you.
分かるな〜。
But don't take me too much ok?
でも、あんまり俺を取らないでくれよ。
Is that an invitation?
ふりか？
No, it's not!
違うから！
Time to go I guess.
さて、行くか〜。
Gyungyun ikuyo!
ギュンギュン行くよ〜。
Let's go!
行くよ〜。
Late greeting but happy new year.
挨拶が遅くなりましたが、あけましておめでとうございます。
Happy new year indeed.
あけましておめでとう〜。
It kind of is February tho.
もう２月なんだがそれは。
Well, it’s the first record of the year. Cannot help it.
いや、なんだかんだ今年初めての記録だから仕方ない。
Have to find a name for this part...
このパートの名前を決めないと。
It's only you and me recording voices at a cafe, so part c is fine I guess?
ただマキさんと俺がファミレスで打ち合わせで 音入れているだけだし、パートCでいいんじゃない？
There isn't a lot of noise for something recorded in public.
ファミレスで撮ってる割には雑音がが少ない気がするな。
You can thank my edit skills.
編集マジックって言ってくれ〜。
Thank you for the views on YouTube.
YouTube上のご視聴頂いてありがとうございます。
I didn't see many views on the YouTube side.
YouTubeだとそこまで視聴数がなかったね。。。
Well… couldn’t promote it too much…
ま〜あんまり広告出来ていないからね。。。
Maybe I should spread it with “Yay! Maki is kawaii”…
今後はﾏｷｻﾝｶﾜｲｲﾔｯﾀｰで広げるべきか。。。
Please don't…
やめてくれ〜。
Moving on,
まあまあ、
Can you react to some comments from NicoNico?
ニコニコからマキさんあての コメントがあるから、リアクションお願い。
I mean it's better than talking about the weather.
いや〜、天気の話よりかはマシな気がするが。
Are you hitting on me?
なんぱですか〜。
Who knows?
さて、どうでしょう？
Yah… but was too busy trying to climb that hill...
あ～、あの時は坂を上がることに集中していたからな。。。
Please don't get into any trouble (this is fiction).
トラブルに巻き込まれないように～（フィクション）。
Is that ok?
これで大丈夫？
Perfect, I think it’ll be fun to watch.
パーフェクト、多分面白い事になっている。
I learn new ways to edit so I hope I’ll get used to editing and posting.
毎回、新しい教訓を見つけると思いますので、 編集・投稿に慣れが出ると思います。
Please look forward to the next record.
良ければ今後の記録もお楽しみください。
Well see you on the next record until then take care.
それでは皆様、また次の記録まで、ご安全に。
See you.
またね〜。
Ah, a message from Aoi. She angry because there was no narration…
あっ、葵ちゃんからメッセージだ、 ナレーションがなかったから怒っている。。。
I wonder if there is narration next time. Ah, there is this question from you.
次回はあるかな。。。あーマキさんのあの疑問があるか。